Michael Slater

UI Focused Web Developer

1234 Elmwood Ave #4D | Evanston, IL 60202 | 773.330.5341 | http://mikeslater.com | slatron@gmail.com

Objective

To advance my career while increasing my web application programming and design skills. I build custom HTML User Interfaces for web apps. I have worked for clients of all sizes, from personal blogs to enterprise online shopping carts.

I understand how to match innovative code with a focus on project objectives. I love exploring code to see how new UI patterns are built. My favorite thing about front end development is discovering an exciting new web technology, then finding a practical use for it.

Relevant Experience

Aug 2014 - Present | Wellspring Worldwide Inc. - Chicago, IL

Sr. Front End Developer

- Create AngularJS Web Client for enterprise SAAS web app
- Work with back end dev team to define API architecture
- Write and maintain application styleguide
- Write and maintain javascript unit tests
- Write and maintain build system with node and gulp
- Integrate jQplot and D3 for data visualization

Dec 2009 - July 2014 | Leapfrogonline.com - Evanston, IL

Sr. Front End Developer

- Developed HTML5/CSS templates for client sites
- Trained front end team on current javascript practices
- Created mobile strategy with UX team
- Implemented Google Analytics strategy across multiple client sites

Feb 2008 - Dec 2009 | Americaneagle.com - Park Ridge, IL

Integrated Solutions Developer

- Work in team-based environment on major NFL and entertainment websites.
- Develop client side websites with HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS and Flash.
- Design and optimize web graphics with Photoshop and Illustrator.

2002 - Present

Independent Web Designer / Developer

- Design, build and maintain websites for clients according to individual needs.
- Diverse clients included restaurants, bands, artists and law firms
- Used PHP, MySql and CodeIgniter to create custom CMS
- Use of Wordpress to create custom themes

Skills

- Expert knowledge of Cross-Browser HTML/CSS integration
- Website templating with HTML5, CSS3 and javascript
- Responsive Web Development
- AJAX connection with RESTful web services
- Google Universal Analytics Implementation
- Client-side build ystems with GUlp and Node
- Unit testing with Jasmine, Karma and Capybara

Languages, Libraries and Platforms

HTML5 Sass
Javascript Compass
CSS Susy

Bootstrap Foundation

jQueryGitKnockoutFirebaseAngularJSPHPReactMySQLAngular2Wordpress

Education

Sep 1996 – May 2000 | Alma College - Alma, MI

Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science

- Graduated May 2000, Magna Cum Laudi
- Languages studied include Java, Pascal, and C / C++

Nov 20th, 2007 | Sun Microsystems Certification

Sun Certified Java Associate

- Self guided preparation for exam

Other Experience

Dec 2006 - Present | Mad Bread Band Inc. - Chicago, IL

Bassist / Webmaster

- Create vocal arrangements for band
- Hold down the low end at shows
- Create and upkeep madbreadband.com

Aug 2003 - May 2008 | Cafe Selmarie - Chicago, IL

Counter Manager / Server

- Counter Manager duties included ordering food and supplies, maintaining the staff schedule, keeping track of inventory, and training staff
- Sales leader among wait staff.

Jan 2006 - May 2006 | Second City Inc - Chicago, IL

Musical Director

- Created sound effects for live touring comedy show
- Performed piano and run sound cues live on stage for comedy act

References provided on request